People's lives are at stake and the
problem gets very real. People might
know about Gen AI and they know it
exists but not much beyond that. But
part of the threat landscape are they
most likely to be missing right now. I
think it's the how the work gets done.
That is something that is not obvious.
We have to assume that the likelihood of
getting breached is higher. If you
assume that you will be breached and you
take the directive of how do I get
better at being breached, that changes
the playbook. No, honeys are one part of
a broader way of approaching the
problem.
Where do you see leaders getting a false
security and safety right now?
I think um there's a comforting story we
tell about AI and security. That same
frontier, tools defending the hospital
are always a step ahead of whoever is
attacking it. My guest today spent his
career on the other side of that
assumption. He'd tell you AI didn't
break healthcare's data security. It
exposed what it was never really working
and it handed attackers a brand new
surface to go after. Welcome to the
Signal Room. I'm Chris Hutchins and my guest
today is Prrenava Aduri, co-founder and
CTO of Bedrock Data, a data security and
governance platform built for the cloud,
software as a service and AI era.
Prrenavo was a founding engineer at
Rubric where he cut his teeth on
ransomware and backup recovery. He led
data risk and compliance products to
AWS, scaling a new line past 200 million
in revenue working directly with Fortune
500 CISOs. And he incubated modern data
governance ideas as an entrepreneur in
residence at Greylock. So when he talks
about securing AI inside a hospital,
it's from the engineer seat, not the
slide deck. Peravo, welcome to the Sigma
Room.
Thank you very much. Great to be here
today. Well, before we get dig in too
much, uh, I'd love for you to just get
tell the people a little bit about who
you are and tell us a little bit about
what Bedrock does.
Absolutely. A little bit about me. We
immigrated to the states when I was
five, grew up in California most of my
life. And uh, I think ever since uh,
ever since I started working, I've
always been in some some flavor of data.
uh whether it was scale out data
storage, whether it was uh scale out
data backup uh or ransomware and data
security for companies that have the
most critical data sets, it's always
been some form of data and including
Bedrock now as well. And a little bit
about what Bedrock does. Bedrock is a
sec data security platform. Bedrock was
built for enterprises of the largest
scales to understand their data,
especially as they're collecting this
data in this AI era more than ever as
that data is rapidly expanding. being
able to make sense of the data that
people are creating and transacting with
and then being able to make sure that
that data is being used correctly. Uh
it's not being used in a way that puts
the company at risk, the c customers
companies at risk. And so where Bedrock
is really at is the intersection of data
and how that data is being used by the
business on a day-to-day basis and now
especially as AI agents come online and
agents are transacting on behalf of
humans, how those agents are making use
of that data as well. We sit at the
center of all of that. And the way we
like to think about it is if you can
ensure that the correct guard rails are
in place, then the company can actually
move fast and realize the value of AI
properly. So that in a nutshell, that's
what we're doing.
Well, you make it sound easy, but I'm
I'm certain that it's not.
Fair enough.
You you spent your early career on
ransomware and backup recovery at
Rubert. What changed about the problem
once the target was a hospital instead
of an ordinary business? The short
answer is uh people's lives are at
stake. Uh and the problem gets very real
very fast. If an adversary performs a
ransom hospital system, they are doing
reconnaissance of what anyone doing a
ransom will do reconnaissance on
figuring out where it will hurt the
target the most such that they have the
maximum likelihood of getting the
successful ransom payment. And in
healthcare, unfortunately, those are
operationally critical systems that may
administer actual medical devices uh and
that are giving life-saving support. It
could be the medical systems. Anything
that gets in the way of a patient
getting care is something that can
affect the outcome of a patient, right?
And unfortunately, there have been
instances where because of ransomware
attacks, people have been impacted very
severely. And so, yeah, the the short
answer to to your question is uh lives
are at stake. uh when when when an
adversary decides to target a hospital
like this.
Yeah. I don't know what makes people
think of the these types of nefarious
things, but it it's just it's alarming
and I'm I'm really glad there's people
like you that are they're that are
really on the front line making sure
that we're constantly monitoring and and
hardening that surface. Um let's bring
this up to today up to today for a
leader who's just starting to pay
attention. People might know about Gen
AI and they know it exists but not much
beyond that. what part of the threat
landscape are they most likely to be
missing right now
when it comes to leaders that are kind
of exploring genai for the whether for
the purposes of transforming their
business or bringing operational
efficiencies I think the part that I
think it's easy for people to kind of
start seeing the light in the sense that
uh oh these are all the ways we can
bring automation these are all the all
the backend processes that uh took
forever in a day that someone had to do
that can now a set of agents can handle,
right? I think the part that's easy to
miss though is you have these actors
that are operating on instructions that
you've given them. But
yeah,
in in terms of making sure that they are
aligned and making sure that they're
acting in a way that exercises the
judgment that a human operator would,
that's the part where it's not obvious
all the ways these things can go rogue.
It's not obvious all the ways that an
agent might in the service of trying to
be helpful and do what you asked it to
do, it might do things that you didn't
want it to do, like keeping the data
somewhere uh where it shouldn't be
because it was it was easier for it to
work off of the data in that new
location that having to uh do it in a
more secure route, right? Uh at the end
of the day, these agents are trying to
get the job done, but how the path that
they take to get the job done, that's
the part that's the unknown. That's the
part that's hard to fathom for people,
right? And so to to answer your question
about where uh what people might be
missing, I think it's the the um the how
the work gets done that is something
that is not obvious when when when
you're when you're setting these agents
to go do a task. There's so many ways
that this is uh similar to other things
that we've we've gone through from a
transformation standpoint. I remember
the first time I used the ways app on my
phone. After first couple times I got to
where I needed to go and then all of a
sudden I started to trust it and then I
get went to a new city things were a
little more compressed and I would start
to miss turns because it couldn't it
wasn't moving that fast. But you know
it's just one of those scenarios where
constantly seeing evolution and adoption
of technologies and it's at a pace where
it's it's just getting a little bit too
fast for people to be able to keep up
and understand what the risks are. I
think there's an assumption that
Frontier AI capability stays on the
defender side. Is that actually true?
I think that it's uh I think despite the
safeguards that Frontier Labs try to put
on these models, I think the consensus
is that it's only a matter of time
before open- source models also catch up
in capabilities, right? And so while the
frontier labs themselves can try to be
responsible with respect to the controls
that they put the vetting that they put
on these models to ensure that only
defenders get the advantage. Take Mythos
for example.
While they can do that while while
they're putting effort into doing that
it's only a matter of time before the
open source community uh and and and
models that are more public available to
the public domain catch up in that in
that tier of capability. And once they
do, the adversary will have just as
powerful tools. Right? So unfortunately,
as as much as uh one would want these to
be used from for one would want these
advanced capabilities on the defensive
side, we have to assume that our
adversaries also in a in a in a matter
of um in a matter of time and that too
soon will have similar capabilities. the
uptick in AI assisted attacks has
already uh it can already be if you look
at uh uh IBM's data breach report uh and
so on and so forth the number of I I
think the the first time in in a while
it's not stol it's not stolen identities
that are the top that are the top cause
for for breaches right it's actually
it's actually um other tactics now that
that that are that are more feasible for
adversaries to leverage because of AI
you it's interesting I I did some
research a couple a few months ago for
the story is and we're just looking at
the fraud and and uh the the cost of
some of the social media fraud that goes
on and I really hadn't thought about it
but I I discovered in that there's the
versions of this technology that we use
like a chat GPT they have their own
version that they're using they're aimed
to they're constant constantly going
back and forth and back and forth we're
trying to increase our ability to detect
they're trying to sub subvert that I I
had no idea. But I I think it's it
raises an an interesting question. The
advantage is not guaranteed this point.
So if both are getting better, I mean
the honest goal we want to get better at
being at not being breached, I think,
but if someone's determined to get to a
hospital can really get hurt um and the
data might actually get penetrated or
worse it leaks out. what's what is
really the honest goal that we have to
think about there
to to your point. I think that um as
these models get more advanced for for
uh I think the the stark reality that
people have to accept is that the
likelihood of getting breached is going
to be higher than a than than than it
was preai. And this is in in spite of
all the investments people might be
making to do better detection and
response, better patching, even with all
that in place. I think the likelihood of
a motivated adversar's ability to get in
is now higher. And so I think
organizations have to start adopting the
mentality of the likelihood of getting
breached is higher. How do I get better
at being breached?
That that's an interesting way to frame
that. It sounds kind of backwards, but
It's a it's it's a little bit of a it's
a little bit of a neck turner when I say
this, but I I I think you have to assume
that for a motivated adversary with all
the tools at their disposal, and we're
still, mind you, we're still in the very
early arc of all of this, the types of
evolutions of these models that we're
going to be seeing in the coming years
are going to be are going to make what
what we have right now look like child's
play. And so we have to assume that that
the likelihood of getting breached is
higher. And so and and and it's it's not
all doom and gloom, right? If you if you
assume that you will be breached and you
take the directive of how do I get
better at being breached, that changes
the playbook now, right? It changes the
playbook in terms of okay, I need to
take a risk based approach to how I'm
doing this. I need to figure out like if
if someone did get in, what are the most
likely places that they could get in?
what are the most valuable targets that
they might be going after? And if I work
backwards from there, I can really start
playing the book from or I can really
start making my moves assuming like
assuming that, right? I can basically
start with for example the the the
heristic that I like to think about is
start with the data that is most
valuable to you. Like if if this data
were compromised, it would be company
ending, right? So what what would the
top five categories of data be if you
just sat down and did that exercise?
Okay, next step. Where is that data
sitting right now? If I know where that
data is sitting right now, I can start
there. Instead of doing an infinite
search of all possible risks, I can
start there and I can start modeling.
Well, if an adversary were to get to
this, what are the roads that they could
take to get to this data? Okay, now
let's focus on those roads. What are the
what are the entry points that that
would allow them to leverage those
roads? And then you can systematically
start hardening and layering the
compensating controls that way. Right?
So for me, a a good way to get better at
getting breached is to start with what
matters the most and work working
backwards from there. It it wasn't
obvious to me u start to look look at
what you've been talking about. I wonder
and maybe this is crazy but if you know
that that's going to happen obviously we
want to harden places that you that you
know about but do you think about ways
to essentially lead the witness so to
speak set some traps for them they take
them off on a tangent way away from
what's really important
so in in in the sense of potentially
having honeypotss that that you can
deploy that is that is one way to go
about it as well right but I think I
think Honey pots are one part of a of a
broader way of approaching the problem,
right? Which is, you know, you can think
about it like, you know, well, since we
were talking about hospitals, right? Key
cards, right? Key cards lead to
hospitals, but
and and you could let's assume that
there's a lot of key cards.
Well, some not all key cards should be
leading to the operational uh theater
rooms. And so if if every key card can
lead there, well, you should probably
start start with what key cards can lead
to these operational rooms and do those
people really need to have access to
those rooms and let's let's let's work
backwards from there, right? And so in
the ideal state, you're monitoring what
are the most critical assets. You're
monitoring the key cards that lead to
them. And if any key cards end up
getting access to these operational data
rooms, you're able to immediately detect
that and respond to it. The the
situation that most organizations find
themselves right now is that because
there's so much data and there's so much
identity in grants, figuring out what
data is most sensitive and what key
cards lead to these the these sensitive
rooms in and of itself is a giant manual
exercise. So imagine instead you have
the ability to continuously keep up with
the data. You have the ability to
understand what that data means to the
business and the impact that that data
has. And you also have the ability to
continuously monitor who who's getting
access, how is this data being used.
Then you can actually start you you can
actually kind of take control of this
now, which is these key cards shouldn't
be having this access anymore. Right? In
the ideal world, if if there's a key
card that's randomly dropped and an
adversary finds it and they they scan it
to get in, they lead to a storage closet
and there's nothing of value there,
right? That's the ideal that's the ideal
situation, right? It should not be
leading to an operating theater room.
Well, it's a it's a natural way for I
mean it helps me to understand to think
think about things differently. But what
does this mean in terms of how AI gets
access and how where where the handoffs
are happening? You know, where the keys
are we're handing the keys and they're
moving around inside and maybe we're not
even aware of it. Um a lot of AI agents
are getting hit in broad access just to
make them work in a clinical setting.
Why is that a real problem?
What does governing an agent's access
actually look like?
In order to make an agent useful, in
order for an agent to give you time back
in your day, you the agent needs to be
able to do useful things and to do those
useful things, it needs access. And and
it's exactly as you mentioned earlier,
you started using ways for a while and
after a first couple of touch points
where it didn't where where it took you
got you to point B in a good amount of
time, you started trusting it. The same
thing happens here. The agent does a
couple of jobs for you. Well, and you
start trusting it and you give you start
giving it more and more access,
right? And that's how that's how the
access extends. The big difference
between agents and humans with access is
agents don't have judgment. Agents have
instructions that they've been given
that they should do certain things and
should not do certain things. But the
judgment of how to evaluate a certain
situation and whether they should or
should not take this path to get into a
certain outcome, that's not guaranteed,
right? And that that's not there either.
And that's the fundamental gap. And so
in a hospital setting for example, if
you are using agents to update records,
you're using agents to perform actions,
the risk can be that in the service of
trying to get the goal done, it might uh
it might take a a set of intermediate
steps that are not aligned with uh how
hospital should be conducting itself,
right? It can go off path, right? Even
in the service of coming back to their
original goal, that's the risk, right?
And so I'll give you an example. We've
we've seen instances where people have
tried to use their agents to build
dashboards to see how um certain metrics
are performing. But in in to build that
dashboard, the data in the source
location wasn't this is actually
something that a Fortune 500 was
experiencing. The source data was not in
an ideal form. So the agent very simply
created a temporary location in a shared
space that a bunch of people had access
to and started copying the information
there because it was easier for it to
use the data in that new location to
build that dashboard in that in that
combined location. And so yeah, it got
the job done, but at the expense of
making that data accessible to everyone
else in the company, right? These are
the types of judgment calls that an
agent wouldn't be able to make unless it
had a scaffolding that in that basically
told it, "Oh, you're about to go off the
guard rails. Don't do that. Right. No,
it's interesting just you doing some
basic stuff that I've been playing
around with. I I see that kind of
behavior and it all of a sudden they
discover it's got off and doing
something that I either a have told it
explicitly not to do or B I I it never
occurred to me that they would do it.
But often times I think we because we
trust so easily we we forget that human
beings make these things. So there's
going to have some tendencies that we
have to be aware and that's right and
the rule that clinical AI has to pass
the tests and it's really doesn't give
time back. And I love that you say that
because I've swung to so many clinicians
that have been so frustrated with with
how we develop technology for them
because we're we've done the opposite of
that. We've been taking time away from
what they went to medical school for
which is really to take care of people.
Does security ever pass that test or
does it always work? Well, I think I
there's no reason security doesn't have
to pass that test. Uh, in security, we
have a rule that that says in order for
someone to truly do the secure thing,
the secured path has to be easier than
the default path because people will
ultimately choose the path of least
resistance to get something done. So, I
think the the onus is on leaders and
uh security innovators to build
solutions that are easy to use. So the
way I think about it is you should still
use the AI to go do a certain task, but
there should be a layer that's guiding
the AI, a scaffolding that is guiding
the AI to if it's about to go do
something off the rails, like keep the
data in a in a shared location for ease
of use, something should say no, that's
not allowed, right? And so AI is very
robust. If you say that's not allowed,
it'll say, "Oh, I guess I can't do that.
Let me figure out what else I can do."
Right? So it is a self-reovering system.
it can handle you saying no to it but
you need that guidance right and so that
that is where um good AI governance good
AI security comes into play right some
system needs to be aware of the data it
needs to be aware of the corporate
policies it needs to be aware of the
actions that are allowed and it needs to
work in hand with the agents to guide
them right and that and and that that
that is where that is exactly the
problem domain that we are thinking
about as well
yeah so let's talk Oh, where this all
goes wrong quietly. There's that I think
we frequently get into this false sense
of comfort and security that we've kind
of touched on it a little bit, but where
do you see leaders getting a false sense
of security and in safety right now?
I think there's a couple of areas. one
is
I think when um these models first came
out, everyone was uh freaked out about
sending data uh to um to third party
Frontier Labs and they they they assumed
that okay well once Amazon hosts it on
the on the Amazon uh Bedrock ecosystem
not to be confused with bedrock data
once Amazon hosts it uh well now now
it's within my uh now it's within my uh
corporate environment so it's safe right
yeah you like the the the
in a way yes the the model now resides
in in a in a VPC that you control but at
the end of the day like if there's
agents getting powered off of that model
everything that we talked about earlier
is still a risk right in terms of the
judgment calls of these agents all of
that is still at risk so I think there's
maybe a a gap where people assume that
okay well we've bought the model within
within our four walls and so the big
risk is over right that's like saying I
put a firewall so I'm good to go not
really right there's
the like there there's still all the
downstream the the model is the engine
right but there's all the downstream act
like uh agents and other workloads that
are using that model that now have
access I think again getting a handle on
what the blast radius is what these
things can do and then reigning the
blast radius in reducing that blast
radius uh making it so that one if an
adversary or an agent is doing something
you're minimizing the harm that it can
And then two also monitoring the agents,
right? I'll give you an example of of
another Fortune 500 that we're working
with. They had an enormous data
analytics environment. This is a
multipetabyte data analytics environment
and it's also an environment where
because it's an analytics environment by
design a lot of people have to have
access to it. There's a lot of key cards
as well.
Yeah. And so to kind of one reduce the
likelihood that an adversary picking up
a key card could get to something
dangerous and to also get themselves
ready for agentic operations as well.
The exercise that they went went down
was one, what is all the sensitive
customer identifiable information in
here, right? Let's find that data and
let's first figure out why that data is
there, right? Is someone actually
actually using it? If they're not, well,
let's decommission that data, right?
Let's reduce that blast radius. That's
let's and in the process they're getting
better at getting breached, right?
They're reducing the footprint that an
adversary could get to. And then what
are the key cards leading to it? Who has
key cards that they're not even using?
Right? Again, a very great a great
starting point to just reduce the key
cards that an adversary could pick up,
right? And then for the remaining key
cards that need to be there that are
actively being used are do these key
cards have access to rooms that the
person's never using? Well, if so, keep
the key card, but reduce the grant from
of that key card to get into that
particular room, right? And so, in this
way, they've significantly hardened
their environment. And so, now all SA
except for a couple of admins, everyone
has a safe view to that data, right? And
so this is an example of coming back to
now agents are giving people time back
and they're they're they're comfortable
letting it run in these environments
because they've reduced the scope of
what these agents can do in the form of
even if they went off the walls. The
fundamental what they can do with the
data is safe. So that's an example of
kind of putting it all together.
You touched on something that that I
think is interesting because it it's it
was the same kind of thing that happened
when we started seeing these visual data
visualization platforms come out and
they kept leaprogging each other. that
still goes on. But the the piece that's
that was disturbing to me as a chief
data officer was every once in a while I
would see a beautiful looking dashboard
and the data was just wrong. And what
what worries me is is the the same
caution that I would I was giving the
leaders that one of the organizations I
was at was that these things may look
official that that's the danger of it.
uh it can make an average Excel jockey
look like a design wizard and the
prettier it is the more they trust it
unfortunately and that's that's the
problem they flip that over and look at
the data access layer um I've always
been bothered by the fact that I would
have developers having full database
level access you know from a clinical
system that sits on top of it we we have
privilege account controls for that but
people dealing with the data
architecture in the back end I felt like
there there was always a level of
exposure
from your experiences, what do you what
you see now, you still see a lot of risk
and exposure because that's just not
understood.
I think that the short answer is yes.
The when we go into accounts, we do see
a lot of privileged access. It's not and
and it's the enemy tends to be it's
because at a certain point in time that
access was warranted when the system was
getting set up
or during the time of a certain
maintenance. The problem is afterwards
people forget to recycle that, right?
People forget to reduce that back down.
And so over time access tends to grow.
It doesn't it doesn't decrease. And so I
I think the the problem that a lot of
teams find themselves in is like when
the problem that a lot of teams find
themselves in is over time because these
ent these access and entitlements grow
when it does come time where all of a
sudden this problem needs to be reckoned
with they they have this forest of
permissions and and it's not even clear
what are all the ways uh someone gets
access to something right and So yeah,
absolutely right. I think people grant
the privilege so that work can get done
but because they don't necessarily
always go redacted after after the fact.
These things grow and become these giant
scary forests over time that that and
that's how people find themselves in
these situations. And now is exactly
when you want these agents to go do work
for you. If you're letting that agent
act as you, that's when that comes back
to to to to
bite because now these again these
agents don't have your judgment. So if
you set them out to do a task and they
have all the grants that you have,
that's when they can start creating
these unintended side effects. It's a I
don't know it's a whole another level of
uh risk that I I've not I never
anticipated seeing anything like this
but but it's always bothered me because
when we I couldn't protect my team
members for example in the healthcare
sector um often times there are these
break the glass or alerts that fire if
you access a privileged account. Uh
great examples colleague he's
informatics he knew what he was doing.
He's actually just doing some
reconciliation and he wasn't paying
attention where he's you know the
numbers or anything. He just making sure
the fields matched up and uh all of a
sudden the security showed up at his
door and they asked him what is he what
is he doing accessing one of the
executives records and and it was like
reality check for him right then and
there. It's like, okay, we need to make
sure that our team understands how all
this stuff works and we need to make
sure we've got safeguards built in at
the database level that prevents this
kind of thing cuz I mean, at the very
least, it's frightening to have a
security person show up at your at your
door when you're just doing your job.
But if it's really got me, it's more the
protection of the team that's having to
work with this stuff that has always
been a concern. I mean, I I really
appreciate you kind of laying this out
because I think leadership needs to have
a better understanding and think of it
from that context because no one wants
to be the one that allows a breach uh
let alone you know does an organization
want that but you know for me it's
investment to really protect your your
team members as much as it is data. If
if one CEO listening takes away a single
thing from our conversation today what
should it be and where could people find
you and Bedrock? I'm quite sure there's
going to be a lot of folks uh that will
have some interest in having a
conversation with you. I think you've
raised some really good concerns.
Yeah. Well, I think if there's one thing
to remember, I think these marbles are
only going to get better. And so the
likelihood of the likelihood of an event
occurring where whether it's a breach,
whether it's an agent going off the
rails, that will only go up. And so
I think um as uh as the founder of uh
reflex security said the phrase I was
using earlier uh learn to get better at
being breached right and I really liked
that phrase that he used right assume
something will happen and so then how do
you prepare for it for my advice is to
start with the data and then work
backwards right data is a data is the
ultimate anchoring function for taking a
riskbased view to cyber start with the
data work backwards And then I think um
I think that that would be the one thing
uh if uh if someone had to remember
something right get better at getting
breached start with the data uh and then
and then work backwards to harden your
environment.
I love it Dur co-founder and CEO CTO of
Bedrock Data the line I'm taking with me
is the goal is never to be unreachable
is to get good at being breached. I I'll
that's going to stay on you for a long
time because it's not it's not uh it's
not obvious for for people who are
living this in this world that you're
living in dealing with this. So it's you
got to get good at being breached so the
day it happens isn't the day everything
stops.
Y being on the room I really really
appreciate your your time today and um
just briefly I want to just give you a
chance to kind of let people know where
to find you online if they want to reach
out to you.
Absolutely. We post regularly on
LinkedIn with what we're our learnings
from the field are think where we see
the industry going. So find us on
LinkedIn and you can also find us at
byrockdata.ai.
So so yeah would love to hear from you
guys and thank you as well Christian.
Thank you. Well thank you and for
listeners. I'll make sure everything's
in the show notes. If you want to follow
up you can definitely uh I'll leave a
trail there for you to find him very
very easily because we're at a time
where we need this kind of expertise uh
on speed the house. So again, thanks so
much for getting on the Signal Room and
to to my guest. I'm Chris Hutchins and
we'll see you next time. That's it for
this episode of the Signal Room. If
today's conversation sparked something
in you, an idea, a challenge, or
perspective worth amplifying, I'd love
to hear from you. Message me on LinkedIn
or visit sigaroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming